Guide to the Dora Erway Doll collection 1924-1928.
Erway, Dora Doll collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dora Erway Doll collection 1924-1928.
23-16-3625
Erway, Dora Wetherbee,
10.6 cubic feet.
Dolls.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Thirty-seven dolls, given to the University Library in 1957, represent various historical periods and nationalities.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor in the Dept. of Household Arts from 1921-1945 and in the Department of Housing and Design from 1945 to1956.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Thirty-seven dolls, given to the University Library in 1957, represent various historical periods and nationalities. Many of the dresses are exact replicas of authentic gowns. with authentic undergarments and hairstyles. Some of the fabrics used in the costumes were over a hundred years old at the time the dolls were made. Students made the dolls themselves as well as the clothing, with the exception of the heads, although many contributed their own hair for their dolls.
Includes photographs of the dolls taken by John Troy in the 1920s.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Erway, Dora Wetherbee,; Troy, John P.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University; Cornell University. Department of Housing and Design.; Cornell University. Department of Household Arts.
Subjects:
Dolls.; Dolls; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Use by appointment only.
CONTAINER LIST
- Egyptian doll; c. 900 B.C., 1924-1928; MU-1 (Box 2)
- Male doll; c. 4th to 6th century, 1924-1928; MU-2 (Box 2)
- Grecian doll; c.1100-850 B.C., 1924-1928; MU-3 (Box 2)
- Roman doll, 1924-1928; MU-4 (Box 2)
- 11th century; Frankish doll, 1924-1928; MU-5 (Box 2)
- 12th century; Norman doll, 1924-1928; MU-6 (Box 3)
- 13th century doll, 1924-1928; MU-7 (Box 3)
- 14th century; French doll; c. 1350, 1924-1928; MU-8 (Box 3)
- 15th century; English doll, 1924-1928; MU-9 (Box 3)
- 16th century; English doll; c. 1536, 1924-1928; MU-10 (Box 4)
- 16th century; Elizabethan doll, 1924-1928; MU-11 (Box 10)
- 17th century; American doll; c. 1620, 1924-1928; MU-12 (Box 4)
- 17th century; French doll; Louis XV, 1924-1928; MU-13 (Box 4)
- 17th century; French doll; Louis XVI, 1924-1928; MU-14 (Box 4)
- 18th century; American doll; c. 1776, 1924-1928; MU-15 (Box 4)
- 18th century; Early Empire French doll; c. 1795, 1924-1928; MU-16 (Box 5)
- 19th century; Empire doll; c. 1825, 1924-1928; MU-17 (Box 5)
- 19th century; American doll; c. 1849, 1924-1928; MU-18 (Box 5)
- 19th century; Italian Renaissance doll; c. 1860, 1924-1928; MU-19 (Box 5)
- 19th century; American Southern-Colonial; c. 1871, 1924-1928; MU-20 (Box 5)
- 19th century; American doll; c. 1872, 1924-1928; MU-21 (Box 6)
- 19th century; American doll; c. 1890, 1924-1928; MU-22 (Box 6)
- 20th century; American Sport doll; c.1927, 1924-1928; MU-23 (Box 6)
- 20th century; American Formal doll; c. 1927, 1924-1928; MU-24 (Box 6)
- 20th century; Alsace-Lorraine doll; c. 1900, 1924-1928; MU-25 (Box 6)
- 18th century; American Indian Male doll, 1924-1928; MU-26 (Box 7)
- 18th century; American Indian Female doll, 1924-1928; MU-27 (Box 7)
- 18th century; Chinese Manchu Male doll, 1924-1928; MU-28 (Box 7)
- 19th century; Chinese Manchu Female doll; c.1890, 1924-1928; MU-29 (Box 7)
- 20th century; India Hindu doll, 1924-1928; MU-30 (Box 8)
- 20th century; Netherlands doll, Volendam, 1924-1928; MU-31 (Box 8)
- 20th century; Norwegian doll, Hardanger, 1924-1928; MU-32 (Box 8)
- 20th century; Peruvian Cuzco Indian doll, 1924-1928; MU-33 (Box 8)
- 20th century; Romanian Peasant doll, 1924-1928; MU-34 (Box 9)
- 20th century; Romanian Nobility (male) doll, 1924-1928; MU-35 (Box 9)
- 20th century; Romanian Nobility, 1924-1928; MU-36 (Box 9)
- 19th century; Spanish Seville doll, 1924-1928; MU-37 (Box 9)